And now we've arrived at an exciting moment in our first week.
이제 첫 주의 흥미진진한 순간이 다가왔어요
The conclusion of the first week is where we get to actually put this into practice and build a commercial
첫 주의 결론은 이 문제를 실제로 실행하고 상업적 해결책을 구축하는 거죠 Get
solution.
up
By the end of today, you will be able to confidently code against the OpenAI API, because you'll have
오늘 내로 오픈AI API에 대해 자신 있게 코드를 작성할 수 있을 겁니다 여러 번
done it several times.
해봤으니까요
You'll have used a technique called one shot prompting that we'll talk about streaming markdown, JSON
원샷 프롬프트라는 테크닉을 사용했을 겁니다 스트리밍 마크다운과 JSON
results, and overall we'll have implemented a business solution literally in minutes.
결과에 관해 얘기할 겁니다 전반적으로 비즈니스 솔루션을 몇 분 만에 구현했어요
So what is this business problem?
사업상의 문제가 뭔가요?
Well, here it is.
여기 있어요
We're going to build an application that is able to generate a marketing brochure about a company.
응용 프로그램을 만들 거예요 그 회사에 대한 마케팅 책자를 생성할 수 있는 거죠
It's something that could be used for prospective clients, for investors or maybe for recruiting talent.
잠재 고객이나 투자자 혹은 인재를 모집할 때 쓸 수 있는 거죠
It's going to be something which will bring together information from multiple sources.
여러 소스에서 정보를 함께 모으는 뭔가가 될 거예요
And so it's a bit like the summarization project we did before, except we're we're summarizing and
전에 했던 요약 프로젝트랑 좀 비슷하죠 비트만 빼고 요약하고 생성하고
we're generating.
있어요
So it's sort of built on top of some stuff we did before.
전에 했던 것 위에 지어진 거죠
Now we're going to use the OpenAI API.
OpenAI API를 사용할 거예요
And as before, you'd be able to switch to using Olama if you wanted to.
전처럼 원하면 올라마를 쓸 수도 있어요
You're now an expert in that, so I'll leave that up to you.
이제 그건 당신이 전문가니까 당신한테 맡길게요
We're going to use a technique called one shot prompting, which sounds very fancy.
원샷 프롬프트라는 테크닉을 사용할 겁니다 아주 근사하게 들리네요
And all it's saying is that in the prompts we send the model, we're going to give an example of what
모델 전송 프롬프트에서 우리가 찾는 것에 대한 예제를 제공한다는
we're looking for.
거죠
We're going to tell it the kind of thing we're expecting it to reply.
답변이 오길 기대하는 그런 걸 알려주는 거죠
And when you do that with one example, it's called one shot prompting.
하나의 예제로 이걸 하는 걸 원샷 프롬프트라고 하죠
If you if you ask a question with no examples at all, that is called zero shot prompting.
예를 전혀 제시하지 않은 질문을 한다면 이것을 제로 샷 프롬프트라고 하죠
It's expected just to figure out from the question how to answer one shot.
한 발에 어떻게 대답할지 문제를 보고 알아내죠
Prompting is when you give one example, and then if you give multiple examples of what you're asking
프롬프트란 하나의 예시를 제시하는 것이고 여러 개의 예시를 제시해 질문을 하고 여러
and what it should respond in different situations, that's known as multi-shot prompting.
상황에서 어떤 반응을 보여야 하는지를 멀티샷 프롬프트라고 해요
So that's that's all there is to it.
그게 다인 것 같아요
And then we're going to be using things like streaming and formatting to make this, uh, nice, nice
그리고 스트리밍과 포맷 같은 걸 이용해서 이 멋지고 인상적인 브로슈어
and impressive brochure generator.
생성기를 만들 거예요
So just to remind you of the environment setup, we've done this to death.
환경 설정 얘길 다시 하자면 우린 이걸 죽도록 했어요
You've got an environment that works and it's fabulous.
잘 맞는 환경을 조성했어요
But just to remind you what you did, you cloned the repo.
하지만 당신이 한 짓을 상기시켜 드리자면 압류 차량을 복제했죠
You followed the readme to set up your Anaconda environment, maybe a virtual env, and you set up a
읽기를 따라 아나콘다 환경 가상 가상 가상 가상 환경을 설정하고 OpenAI로
key with OpenAI and you put that key, the OpenAI API key, which is src proj.
키를 설정해 OpenAI API 키를 입력합니다 src proj죠
Blah blah blah.
어쩌고저쩌고 말이죠
You put that in a file that was called dot env and it is in your project root directory.
그걸 .Infi라는 파일에 넣으면 프로젝트 루트 디렉터리에 있죠
And that is why all of this is working so well.
그래서 이 모든 게 잘 풀리는 거예요
And so what you need to do now in order to get us back to where we were, is if you're on a PC, you
이전으로 돌아가기 위해 해야 할 일은 get attt pc라면 아나콘다 프롬프트를
bring up an Anaconda prompt.
띄우는 거예요
If you're on a mac, you bring up a terminal window.
맥을 사용하면 터미널 윈도우를 띄워요
You go to the project root directory LM engineering.
프로젝트 루트 디렉터리 LM 엔지니어링으로 가세요
You type the conda, activate lm conda, activate LM to activate the environment.
콘다를 입력하고 lm 콘다를 활성화하면 환경을 활성화할 수 있죠
And then you should see the LMS prefix by your prompt.
그럼 프롬프트 옆에 LMS 접두사가 보일 거예요
If it already says that, then you're already activated.
이미 그렇게 말하면 이미 활성화 된 거죠
And once you've done that, you simply type JupyterLab to launch JupyterLab and to be up and running.
그렇게 하고 나면 JupyterLab을 입력해 JupyterLab을 시작하고 실행하게 하면 돼요
And that is where I will see you in the next video.
다음 영상에서 다시 만나요